Guide to the Hans Caspar Syz Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1917-1991; Series I
  - Horizon Press [regarding publication of A. S. Galt's Toward Social Sanity and Human Survival ], 1981-1987 (Box 7, Folder 126-127)
  - Hubbard, Barbara, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Hull, James, 1958 -1972 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Humphreys, Edward, 1935-1988 (Box 7, Folder 130-132)
  - Hurttlen, Christa, 1973-1985 (Box 7, Folder 133-137)
    box 77, folder 2-3
  - I (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - Illing, Hans, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - International Cooperation Year Conference, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - J (Box 7, Folder 141-142)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1937-1980 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, 1926-1933 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - K (Box 7, Folder 146-148)
  - Keller, Tina, 1960-1984 (Box 8, Folder 149-152)
    box 64, folder 154
  - Kelman, Harold, 1960-1973 (Box 8, Folder 153)
  - Kendig, Marjorie, 1950-1979 (Box 8, Folder 154-155)
    box 5, folder 102
    box 8, folder 159
  - Kinder, Elaine, 1927-1940 (Box 8, Folder 156-157)
  - Klages, Ludwig, 1910-1939 (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - Korzybski, Alfred, 1927-1939 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    box 8, folder 154-155
  - L (Box 8, Folder 160-163)
  - LaGarde, Beata and Richard, 1938-1987 (Box 8, Folder 164-165)
  - Langner, Thomas, 1955-1962 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Larsen, A.K., 1955-1970 (Box 9, Folder 167)
  - Latham, Paul, 1965-1972 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Lawrence, D.H. [centennial correspondence], 1986 (Box 9, Folder 169)
  - Luncan, Alexander, 1955-1984 (Box 9, Folder 170)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 171-181)
  - MacIver, Fraser, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 182)
  - Malisoff, William, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Mann, Thomas, 1940-1982 (Box 9, Folder 184)
    box 4, folder 65
  - Margenau, Henry, 1958 - 1960 (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - Marshall, Louise, 1966-1974 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - May, Rollo, 1960-1983 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - Merker, Björn, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 188-189)
    box 62, folder 92
  - Merker, Björn, 1970-1991 (Box 10, Folder 190-192)
  - Meyer, Adolf, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 193)
  - Moreno, J. L., 1956-1967 (Box 10, Folder 194)
  - N (Box 10, Folder 195-198)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1931-1940 (Box 10, Folder 199-200)
  - Needleman, Jacob [Penguin Books], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 201)
  - New England Psychological Association, 1955-1972 (Box 10, Folder 202)
  - New School for Social Research
    box 6, folder 107
    box 6, folder 113
    box 9, folder 185
    box 9, folder 187
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1930-1984 (Box 10, Folder 203-204)
  - New York Hospital
    box 57, folder 19
    - Cornell College, 1929-1962 (Box 10, Folder 205-209)
    - Old Unit, 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 210)
  - New York State and County Medical Society, 1930-1951 (Box 10, Folder 211-212)
  - New York State Psychiatric Institute, 1930-1938 (Box 11, Folder 213)
    box 57, folder 12
    box 57, folder 13
  - O (Box 11, Folder 214-215)
  - Ohtsuki, Kenji [Burrow's translator into Japanese], 1956-1975 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    box 61, folder 71
  - Opler, Marvin, 1956-1968 (Box 11, Folder 217)
  - P (Box 11, Folder 218-221)
  - Pfister, Oskar, 1924-1931 (Box 11, Folder 222)
  - Philosophical Library [publishers], 1953-1982 (Box 11, Folder 223-225)
  - Piotrowski, Zygmunt, 1931-1952 (Box 11, Folder 226)
  - Poole, Dana, 1965-1984 (Box 11, Folder 227)
  - Pope, Arthur [American Institute for Iranian Art and Archaeology], 1938-1972 (Box 11, Folder 228-229)
  - Prince, Raymond, 1965-1984 (Box 11, Folder 230-231)
  - Q (Box 11, Folder 232)
  - R (Box 11, Folder 233-237)
  - Read, Herbert, 1946-1968 (Box 11, Folder 238-239)
    box 45, folder 81
  - Richter, Curt, 1926-1934 (Box 12, Folder 240)
  - Riese, Hertha, 1974-1981 (Box 12, Folder 241-242)
    box 12, folder 243-245
  - Riese, Walther, 1952-1976 (Box 12, Folder 243-245)
    box 45, folder 82
    box 45, folder 85
    box 45, folder 86
    box 64, folder 155
  - Rosenzweig, Saul, 1938-1981 (Box 12, Folder 246)
  - S (Box 12, Folder 247-254)
  - Sachs, Eugene, 1968-1986 (Box 12, Folder 255)
  - Sankaran, C.R., 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 256)
  - Sato, Koji, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 257)
  - Schelbert, Leo [Swiss American Historical Society], 1969-1983 (Box 13, Folder 258-261)
    box 65, folder 162
  - Schultz, J.H., 1951-1961 (Box 13, Folder 262)
  - Selver, Charlotte, 1972-1981 (Box 13, Folder 263)
  - Shields, Clarence, 1929-1947 (Box 13, Folder 264)
    box 63, folder 110
  - Sill, Alfreda Payson, 1938-1982 (Box 13, Folder 265)
    box 63, folder 111
  - Staal, Frits [University of California, Berkeley, Department of Philosophy], 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 266)
  - Staehlin, Balthasar, 1972-1975 (Box 13, Folder 267)
  - State University of New York, 1926-1929 (Box 13, Folder 268)
  - Stein, Leo, 1928-1947 (Box 13, Folder 269)
  - Stern, Mark, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 270)
  - Stettler, Michael, 1956-1983 (Box 13, Folder 271)
  - Stokvis, Berthold [Psychosomatisch Centrum, Netherlands; Acta Psychotherapeutica et Psychosomatica ], 1961-1963 (Box 13, Folder 272)
  - Strass, Herbert, 1957-1958 (Box 13, Folder 273)
  - Swiss Medical Committee, 1942-1947 (Box 13, Folder 274)
  - Syz, Stephan, 1967-1988 (Box 13, Folder 275)
  - T (Box 13, Folder 276-277)
  - Theologischer Verlag Zürich, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 278)
  - Tomita, Giske, 1955-1972 (Box 13, Folder 279)
  - U (Box 13, Folder 280)
  - V (Box 13, Folder 281)
  - Valliant, René, 1934-1981 (Box 13, Folder 282)
  - Vinekar, S. L., 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 283)
  - W (Box 14, Folder 284-288)
  - Wallace, Kevin [ New Yorker ], 1949-1979 (Box 14, Folder 289)
  - Watson, Goodwin, 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 290)
  - Wertham, Fredric, 1926-1981 (Box 14, Folder 291)
  - Whyte, Lancelot Law, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 292)
  - Wick, Erika, 1972-1981 (Box 14, Folder 293)
  - Wittkower, Erich, 1932-1965 (Box 14, Folder 294)
  - Woollcott, Philip Jr., 1968-1988 (Box 14, Folder 295-297)
  - Wunderli, Juerg, 1972-1981 (Box 14, Folder 298)
  - X, Y (Box 14, Folder 299)
  - Yale University Library, 1980-1985 (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Z (Box 14, Folder 301)
- Notes, 1915-1982, undated; Series II
  This series comprises three kinds of notes kept by Syz: autobiographical sketches, topical notes and reading excerpts. Syz's autobiographical notes contain introspective commentaries on his research, events in the Lifwynn community and his family life. The topical notes and excerpts are more directly related to his writings, and carbon copies from these files can be found among the notes and drafts of many papers in Series III. The collection of reading excerpts consists primarily of quotations from and summaries of books and articles, and are rarely accompanied by critique or commentary.
  The autobiographical writings are arranged chronologically. Of particular interest to researchers investigating the activities of the Lifwynn Foundation are the extensive notes written between 1928 and 1929, which comment on the early experiments in group analysis at the Lifwynn camp. These reflections complement the transcripts of group analytic discussions ("Table Notes") of Series V. The notes Syz wrote following his retirement, between 1962-1968, offer his retrospective look at his career and speculations on the future of the Lifwynn Foundation. Related material can be found in Syz's unpublished reflections on the Lifwynn Foundation in Series III.
  The topical notes form the basis of Syz's research projects and writings, and are a good source of information for researchers interested in Syz's intellectual development. Syz's original collection of topical notes is preserved in its alphabetical arrangement by subject heading. These typically contain telegraphic paper outlines, memos, bibliographies and clippings. A short series of notebooks and binders ("Topical binders") containing brief annotated bibliographies and reading lists for papers in progress is appended to the first set of topical notes. A second set of topical notes is arranged by date. These follow a standardized format and contain thumbnail sketches of research questions and more thorough formulations of the theoretical reflections found in the autobiographical notes. The formulation of these notes seems to have been an important part of Syz's everyday research activities, as he compiled them steadily between 1925 and 1974.
  The collection of excerpts developed by Syz and other members of the Lifwynn Foundation was also used extensively in Syz's writing projects. They are arranged alphabetically by author's name. If an excerpted piece had multiple authors, it is listed under the name of the first author. The few excerpts from presentations made at conferences or panels are listed under the name of the sponsoring organization or the name of the meeting's chair. They are drawn primarily from published books and articles but occasionally from radio and television programs, lectures, unpublished writings, and correspondence. The selections are informative in so far as they reveal what aspects Syz considered to be the most interesting or relevant of the many authors he read. Although the majority of the excerpts date from between 1950 and 1965, they also reflect the evolution of his interests. Early excerpts concentrate on neurobiological and psychoanalytical publications. Beginning in the 1930s, excerpts from writings in a wider range of human sciences, such as Gestalt and evolutionary psychology, anthropology and sociology, become more prevalent. Authors who constituted Syz's immediate intellectual community (those writing about group psychotherapy and social psychiatry) are particularly well-represented.
  The excerpts are distinguished from memos of conversations with individuals, which are located in Series I under the name of the interviewee, and conference reports made by Lifwynn staff members, which are located in Series V.
  A subject index of the excerpts can be found at the end of the series. Syz had originally kept two series of excerpts, one organized alphabetically by subject and one by author's name. These were merged, but because the two versions were not identical, the subject index is not completely comprehensive.
  - Autobiographical and personal notes
    - 1915-1928 (Box 15, Folder 1-21)
    - 1929-1949 (Box 16, Folder 22-42)
    - 1950-1971 (Box 17, Folder 43-67)
    - 1970-1982, undated (Box 18, Folder 68-79)
  - Topical notes
    - Alphabetical
      - Aggression, Circa 1943 (Box 18, Folder 80)
      - Autistic image dependence, 1955-1968 (Box 18, Folder 81)
      - Behavioral observations, 1933-1936 (Box 18, Folder 82)
      - Biology, physiology, 1925-1927 (Box 18, Folder 83)
      - Consciousness, 1931-1933 (Box 18, Folder 84)
      - Cooperative society, Undated (Box 18, Folder 85)
      - Cotention
        - Notes, 1954-1964 (Box 18, Folder 86)
        - Observations, 1947-1965 (Box 18, Folder 87)
      - Cultural trends, 1929-1933 (Box 18, Folder 88)
      - Dream material, 1951-1955 (Box 18, Folder 89)
      - Definition, 1932-1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 90)
      - Economics, 1929-1935 (Box 18, Folder 91)
      - Ego, 1925-1927 (Box 18, Folder 92)
      - Emotions, 1924-1927 (Box 18, Folder 93-94)
      - Group analysis
        - Notebook, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 95)
        - Additional material, 1928-1973 (Box 19, Folder 96)
      - Group approach, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 97)
      - Group technique, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 98)
      - Historical development, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 99)
      - Human nature, ca., 1942-1947 (Box 19, Folder 100)
      - Industry and economics, 1931-1934 (Box 19, Folder 101)
      - Instincts: sex, 1924-1927 (Box 19, Folder 102)
      - Integration
        - 1929-1932 (Box 19, Folder 103)
        - 1942-1967 (Box 19, Folder 104)
      - Intellectual position, Circa 1926 (Box 19, Folder 105)
      - Jung, Jungian psychology, Undated (Box 19, Folder 106)
      - Literature and psychoanalysis, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 107)
      - Model, Circa 1931-1964 (Box 19, Folder 108-110)
      - Morality, Circa 1925-1934 (Box 19, Folder 111-112)
      - Neural mechanisms, Circa 1934 (Box 19, Folder 113)
      - Neurotic personalities, Circa 1931-1934 (Box 19, Folder 114)
      - Nietzsche, 1915-1929 (Box 19, Folder 115)
      - Organic - functional [clinical notes on organically- based pathology], Circa 1931-1936 (Box 19, Folder 116)
      - Organic psychology, Circa 1924-1926 (Box 19, Folder 117)
      - Organismic approach, Circa 1935-1937 (Box 19, Folder 118)
      - Parent-child, 1924-1926 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Perspective and prejudice, Circa 1947 (Box 19, Folder 120)
      - Phenomenology, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 121)
      - Phyletic-global, 1966-1970 (Box 19, Folder 122)
      - Phyloanalytic procedure, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 123)
      - Phylo-organism, Circa 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 124)
      - Preconscious material, 1923-1926 (Box 20, Folder 125)
      - Preconscious, 1959-1961 (Box 20, Folder 126)
      - Primitives, 1928-1934 (Box 20, Folder 127)
      - Principles, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 128)
      - Problems, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 129)
      - Proprioceptive techniques, 1957-1963 (Box 20, Folder 130)
      - Psychopathological mechanisms, 1923-1933, undated (Box 20, Folder 131-133)
      - Psychopathology [drafts of paper], 1931-1932 (Box 20, Folder 134)
      - Quotations, 1931-1958 (Box 20, Folder 135)
      - Religious trends, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 136)
      - Resistance, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 137)
      - Scientific method, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 138-139)
      - Scientific principles, Undated (Box 20, Folder 140)
      - Self, 1931-1933 (Box 20, Folder 141)
      - Self-consciousness, 1926-1927 (Box 20, Folder 142)
      - Social analysis, 1926-1928 (Box 20, Folder 143)
      - Social collusion, 1926-1927 (Box 20, Folder 144)
      - Social forces, 1937-1938 (Box 20, Folder 145)
      - Social integration, Circa 1915-1927 (Box 20, Folder 146-147)
      - Social psychiatry, Undated (Box 20, Folder 148)
      - Special problems, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 149)
      - Subjective aspect; mood, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 150)
      - Subjectivity, 1925-1937 (Box 20, Folder 151)
      - Substitutions; images, 1924-1927 (Box 20, Folder 152)
      - Symbol; language, 1958-1962 (Box 20, Folder 153)
      - Technic, 1925-1927 (Box 20, Folder 154)
      - Terminology, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 155)
      - Transference, 1926-1936 (Box 20, Folder 156)
      - Transference and psychotherapy, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 157-158)
      - Types, Circa 1926-1930 (Box 20, Folder 159)
      - Unitary principle, 1958-1973 (Box 20, Folder 160)
      - Various topics, 1932-1938 (Box 21, Folder 161-163)
      - Words, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 164)
    - Topical binders
      - Literature [annotated bibliography, arranged alphabetically by topic], Undated (Box 21, Folder 165-167)
      - Miscellaneous problems [telegraphic notes and annotated bibliography], Undated
        - A-M (Box 21, Folder 168)
        - N-Z (Box 21, Folder 169)
      - Miscellaneous topics [binder containing alphabetically organized topical notes], Undated (Box 21, Folder 170)
      - Topics [telegraphic notes and annotated bibliography], 1950-1965
        - A-F (Box 21, Folder 171)
        - G-P (Box 21, Folder 172)
        - Q-Z (Box 21, Folder 173)
      - Various comments [notes on authors and topics, often dated], 1946-1948 (Box 21, Folder 174-176)
      - Various notes, Circa 1950
        - A-M (Box 21, Folder 177)
        - N-Z (Box 21, Folder 178)
      - Chronologically organized topical notes
        - 1925-1953 (Box 22, Folder 179-197)
        - 1954-1974, undated (Box 23, Folder 198-215)
    - Excerpts
      - Abl-Bink (Box 24, Folder 216-235)
      - Bins-Burr (Box 25, Folder 236-258)
      - Burt-Eze (Box 26, Folder 259-276)
      - Fab-Gut (Box 27, Folder 277-294)
      - Häab-Jun (Box 28, Folder 295-313)
      - Kab-Loo (Box 29, Folder 314-330)
      - Lor-Noy (Box 30, Folder 331-352)
      - Obe-Rosec (Box 31, Folder 353-372)
      - Rosen-Spa (Box 32, Folder 373-388)
      - Sro-Usd (Box 33, Folder 389-405)
      - Val-Züt (Box 34, Folder 406-423)
    - Subject index to excerpts
      - Adler - Cultural anthropology (Box 35, Folder 406-423)
      - Cybernetics - General systems (Box 36, Folder 406-423)
      - Group dynamics - Memory (Box 37, Folder 406-423)
      - Mental health - Psychiatric theory (Box 38, Folder 406-423)
      - Psychoanalysis - Psychosomatic (Box 39, Folder 406-423)
      - Psychotherapy - Social intervention (Box 40, Folder 406-423)
      - Social neurosis - World peace (Box 41, Folder 406-423)
- Writings and Research Materials, 1911-1987, undated; Series III
  This series consists of material generated by the writing of Syz's articles, books, essays, reviews and research reports, and are arranged into three sections: published writings, unpublished writings, and data records. With the exception of the data records, which were used in the preparation of several published and unpublished papers, the materials used in the research and writing process are included with the manuscripts to which they relate. This material has been arranged to follow as closely as possible the order in which it was produced (e.g., notes followed by drafts, typescripts and revisions). Syz's writings on ceramics are located in Series VI.
  Published writings are organized by type of material and date of publication and include thirty-two articles, two books and fourteen reviews. The first file of the section contains citations of and references to Syz's papers collected by the Lifwynn staff.
  The first nine folders of the unpublished writings contain plans and abstracts for unwritten papers. These are organized by date. Because the span dates of Syz's unpublished works tend to overlap, the manuscripts in the remainder of the series are arranged alphabetically by title or heading. Titles are enclosed in quotation marks, while works in progress having no final title are classified on the basis of provisional headings used by Syz, without quotation marks (e.g., Acta paper, Basic reorientation). Manuscripts that were given both a provisional heading and a final title are arranged according to the title, with headings cross-referenced. The manuscripts exist in various stages of completion. Some papers, while not printed, were read at conferences or other professional meetings; other projects remain in the form of notes. Unpublished articles, reviews and book-length manuscripts are interfiled in this section.
  A handful of longer manuscripts, including 'Phyloanalysis,' `Studies in Phyloanalysis,' `Applications,' and `Therapy' seem intended as books or monographs; chapter or section breaks are indicated where known. Other plans for larger works can be found under the heading `Trigant Burrow's Thesis' and `Notes for Book'. Three longer works, 'Annotations,' 'Basic Awareness and Being,' and 'Monograph' were written during the preparation of Syz's philosophical memoirs, Of Being and of Meaning (Vom Sein und vom Sinn). It seems that Syz had originally intended these notes to serve as the core of a larger work, including his reflections on his career and the Lifwynn Foundation. For readers interested in Syz's biography, these unpublished drafts are valuable supplements to Of Being and of Meaning.
  The data records derive primarily from the studies in physiological psychology Syz performed at Johns Hopkins. Rorschach records used in his clinical research can be found in Series IV.
  - Published
    - Catalogue of citations for Syz's writings, chronological, 1926-1968 (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
    - Articles
      - "On the Entrance of Convulsant Dyes into the Substance of the Brain and Spinal Cord after an Injury to these Structures," Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, Vol. XXI, No. 5 [reprint], 1923 (Box 42, Folder 4)
        box 56, folder 371-372
      - "On the Influence of Asphyxia upon the Action of Convulsant Dyes and upon their Entrance into the Substance of the Central Nervous System. II," Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, Vol. XXX, No. 1 [reprint], 1926 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - "Psychogalvanic Studies on Sixty-four Medical Students," British Journal of Psychology (General Section), Vol. XVII, Part I [reprint and drafts], 1926 (Box 42, Folder 6)
        box 55, box 56, folder 365-370
      - "Observations on the Unreliability of Subjective Reports of Emotional Reactions," British Journal of Psychology (General Section), Vol. XVII, Part 2 [reprint and drafts], 1926 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - "Psychogalvanic Studies in Schizophrenia," Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry, Vol. 16 [reprint, presentation materials and drafts], 1925-1926 (Box 42, Folder 8)
        See also: boxes 55 and 56, folders 365-370
      - "Observations on Experimental Convulsions with Special Reference to Permeability Changes," American Journal of Psychiatry, Vol. VII, No. 2 [reprint of original, German publication and notes], 1927 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - "On a Social Approach to Neurotic Conditions," Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, Vol. 66, No. 6 [notes, reprint of original and German publications], 1927 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - "Electrical Skin Resistance in Normal and in Psychotic Subjects," Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry, Vol. 19 [notes, presentation material and reprint], 1928 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - "Remarks on Group Analysis," [reprint], 1928 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - "Socio-individual Principles in Psychopathology," Vol. X, The British Journal of Medical Psychology, Part IV [notes, drafts and reprint], 1930
        box 78, folder 26
        - Notes, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 13-14)
        - Drafts and reprint, 1929-1930 (Box 42, Folder 15-16)
      - "The Galvanic Skin-reflex: Further Aspects in Psychopathologic Groups," Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry, Vol. 26 [draft and reprint], 1931 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - "Posttraumatic Loss of Reproductive Memory and its Restoration through Hypnosis and Analysis," The Medical Record, October 7 [reprint], 1936 (Box 42, Folder 18)
        box 42, folder 22-29
        box 77, box 78, folder 5-25
      - "The Concept of the Organism-as-a-whole and its Application to Clinical Situations," Human Biology, Vol. 8, No. 4, 1936
        - Notes, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 19)
        - Draft and reprint, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - "Recovery from Loss of Mnemic Retention after Head Trauma," The Journal of General Psychology, Vol. 2, second half, 1937
        box 42, folder 19
        - German sources, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 21-22)
        - English sources, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 23)
        - Drafts, 1935-1937 (Box 43, Folder 24-26)
        - Clippings, 1935-1939 (Box 43, Folder 27)
        - Reprint, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 28)
      - "The `Social Neurosis', The American Journal of Sociology ", Vol. XLII [typescript], 1937 (Box 43, Folder 29)
      - "Phylobiological Aspects of Forensic Psychiatry," [notes and reprint], 1938 (Box 43, Folder 30)
      - "Burrow's Differentiation of Tensional Patterns in Relation to Behavior Disorders," The Journal of Psychology, Vol. 9 [drafts and reprint], 1940 (Box 43, Folder 31)
      - "Letter to the Editor," The American Journal of Sociology, Vol. XLVIII, No. 6 [reprint], 1943 (Box 43, Folder 32)
      - "Therapy within the Group as a Biological Entity," The American Journal of Orthopsychiatry, Vol. XIV, No. [reprint], 1944 (Box 43, Folder 33)
      - "The Lifwynn Eye-Movement Camera," Science, Vol. 103, No. 2681 [reprint], 1946 (Box 43, Folder 34)
      - Letter to Heraldika, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 35)
      - "Phylopathology," Encyclopedia of Psychology, Philip Lawrence Harriman (Ed.) [notes, drafts and reprint], 1946 (Box 43, Folder 36)